So let's have a look at more prompt engineering techniques to improve your
prompt. So first of all, there is something called zero shut prompting.
So this is to present a task to a model without providing any examples or
explicit training for that specific task.
So we have a very general Gen A model, a foundation model.
And for example, we say write a short story about a dog that helps solve a
mystery. And then we get a response from the Gen A model.
For example, once upon a time, there was a clever dog named max and so on.
So this is when we rely fully on the models general knowledge and the larger and
the more capable the foundation model, the more likely we're going to get good
results. It's called zero shut prompting because we go right away and we present
our prompts. Next, we have few shots prompting.
So here we provide examples of a task to the model to make sure we have guided
its outputs. So that's why it's called few shots because we provide few shots
to the model to perform the task. So let's take the exact same prompt as
before, but now we're going to use the few shots prompting technique.
So we say here are two examples of stories where animals help solve mysteries.
And we talk about whiskers, the cats and we write the story and we talk about
buddy the bird and we also write the story.
So now we've provided a few examples to the Gen A model and now we say
write a short story about a dog that helps solve a mystery.
And because we have provided a few shots to the general model, then it's able
to respond in a way that follows the few shots we have provided before.
And so therefore, this is a good technique when you know exactly what kind
of output you want and you want the model to write a new output based on
examples you provide. Also, if you provide only one example,
this is also called one shot or single shot prompting.
Then we have chain of foot prompting.
So here we divide the task into a sequence of reasoning steps leading to
a more structure and coherence.
So when we use a sentence in our prompt, such as think step by step,
this will help the model go into a chain of foot prompting.
So this is very helpful when you want to solve a problem as a human and
that usually requires a several steps.
So for example, let's again do our prompt that we'd say, let's write a story
about a dog solving a mystery.
But then we say first, describe the setting and the dog, then introduce the
mystery, next show how the dog discovers clues and finally reveal how the dog
solves the mystery and concludes the story.
And so therefore we say, write a short story following this plant.
Think step by step and the response will follow this structure and therefore
this is chain of foot prompting.
And this can be combined with zero shots or few shots prompting if you want it
to. Next, we have retrieval augmented generation or rag.
So here we combine the model's capability with external data sources in order
to create a more informed and contextually rich response.
So as a memory, as a reminder, we go and ask something to the
geniam model and some parts of the model is going to retrieve relevant
information from an external data source.
And then we add this as an enhanced prompt and augmented prompt and then we
get the answer from it.
So this is the whole idea behind rag.
So here we can have rag in a way like this.
For example, we say write a short story about a dog solving a mystery and
then use the following information from the text about dogs in their
behavior and details about common mysteries involving theft.
And so we provide a lot of information to the model such as the dogs have
an excellent sense of smell, which they use to track sense and then common
neighborhood mysteries often involve stolen or missing items.
And then dogs can detect sense even from a day old and follow trails.
We locate items.
And so this information can come from an external data source and that is
being added.
This is what's called augmented generations being augmented into our main
prompt.
And therefore we say write the story considering this details.
And of course, well, them, the stories is going to, of course, be guided
towards dogs having a great sense of smell and locating missing items.
So this is how rag works.
We've seen it already at length in the bedrock session, but it was good for
you to see it again here as a little reminder.
So I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.